The following iterative sequence is defined for the set of positive integers:

n → n/2 (n is even)
n → 3n + 1 (n is odd)

Using the rule above and starting with 13, we generate the following sequence:

13 → 40 → 20 → 10 → 5 → 16 → 8 → 4 → 2 → 1
It can be seen that this sequence (starting at 13 and finishing at 1) contains 10 terms. Although it has not been proved yet (Collatz Problem), it is thought that all starting numbers finish at 1.

Which starting number, under one million, produces the longest chain?

NOTE: Once the chain starts the terms are allowed to go above one million.

---------------------------------------------------------------------

Mathematically, my program used the following simple insight - If a number u goes a to a number v in it's collatz sequence.
Then, Collatz Length(u) = Path_length(u-v) + collatz Length (v).

Whenever COllatz Length of v is already known, we save time.

Computationally, there was an overflow error because if the numbers go to a million, the data type has to be big enough to hold them.
For some reason printf wasn't able to print two long long data types in the same answer.
Lastly, once a sequence starts it may go above a million, so I had to ensure, that the compiler never checks the value of Collatz Length(v), when v > 1000000,
Because it would add a junk value.

---------------------------------------------------------------------

The number with the maximum length sequence is 837799.It has 524 terms in it's Collatz sequence.
