n! means n × (n − 1) × ... × 3 × 2 × 1

For example, 10! = 10 × 9 × ... × 3 × 2 × 1 = 3628800,
and the sum of the digits in the number 10! is 3 + 6 + 2 + 8 + 8 + 0 + 0 = 27.

Find the sum of the digits in the number 100!

--------------------------------------------------

The correct answer is 648. For some reason it shows 805 on CodeBlocks. The same program copy pasted on ideone gives the correct answer.
The mistake was that I didn't initialise sum = 0 in the beginning. So, some junk value was getting added. It's funny I made that mistake.
I've never done it ever since I learnt programming. But, in the past whenever I did not initialise it, nothing happened. 
The compiler did it by default I guess.
Now, I learnt why it should be done and not to take the compiler for granted.

Well, as for the algorithm. 100 ! is about 160 digits long. It's too long for any numerical data type in C.

So, I just made an array of size 160. And will treat the number as a collection of 160 single digits.

The program thinks of the array as just a collection of 160 numbers. But, to us it is a number.
This is not trivial. The program treats the array as a collection of numbers. That means that number[]*100, will not have any meaning.
Worse, it may interpret it as multiplying all of the digits of number by 100.

So, all we have to do now that we've thought about the number as a collection of single digits is to define the multiplication process ourselves.

1. Initialise ! This is very important to avoid overflow and addition of junk to the answer. All the digits of number[] should be set to zero. 
Don't assume the compiler will do it.

2. Define the factorial function. The number 100! is huge, but 100 is a small number. 
So, I chose to store the number who's factorial I want as an integer, rather than another array for convenience. 
It's easier to write a function to multiply a numerical data type with the array than multiply two arrays.
(For example, if we were multiplying 100 with the array, and we thought of 100 as an array, then we'd have to add (0 x number) + 10(0* number) + 100(1*number). )
Three auxillary arrays would be needed. This isn't necessary.

Basically, here's what the algorithm I'm doing does. 100 x abcdef.
100 x f = x (say)

x is clearly greater than 10.
Now, x = 10*y + l (where l is a single digit)

y is taken as the carry. The number is now rewritten abcdel.

100 x e + y = x' 

Same process. The modulus with 10 of the product is taken. The carry is also gotten and added to the next number.

A couple of things to be noted - 

1. Have a variable called first_digit, which keeps track of the first digit from the left (The MSD). 
There will be many trailing zeroes. In the example above, there are only 6 digits.
There's no need to run through all 160 digits each time. Only go as far as is necessary.

2. If there's a carry in the most significant digit, then the value of first_digit has to be increased and a new MSD is gotten.

The number of multiplications is the same as the number of digits in number.

So, 
carry = 0; (No carry for least significat digit ... first digit from right)
for(i = 0 to i = first_digit)
	product = num*number + carry;
	replace = num%base; (We're in base 10)
	carry = num/10;

	num[i] = replace //Rewrite first digit

	if( (i == first_digit) & (carry > 0) )
		first_digit++ //So, the process gets repeated once more and the carry over the MSD is not lost. 

---------------

This multiplies with number[] with num. Put the entire thing in another loop which takes num from 1 till 100 to get 100 !
Of course, number[0] has to be intialised to 1. Otherwise, the answer will always be zero.
